Karmesh827@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/karmeshpatel1

SUMMARY

Salesforce Certified Administrator/Developer with 2+ years of experience. Experienced with working in the salesforce cloud, highly skilled in creating Lightning Components. Strong knowledge of Apex classes, triggers, and SOQL queries. Worked as Developer and Business Analyst for full-cycle projects, to complete consulting projects on time, and deliver outstanding consulting services to the client.

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Proficient in: Apex, Java, Javascript, Html/CSS, SLDS, Lightning Components
- Familiar with: Visualforce, Flows, Process Builder, Workflow
- Certifications: Salesforce Admin, Salesforce Developer, Salesforce App Builder, Vlocity

EXPERIENCE

Salesforce Developer

7/2019-Present

Tata Consultancy Services

- Created many Lightning Components and server-side controllers to meet the business requirements.
- Implemented Apex Triggers and Scheduled Classes for automation of the business process.
- Integrated Salesforce.com with external systems like Oracle and SAP using SOAP API and REST API.
- Worked with Business System Analyst to provide recommendation and designed the Best Solutions for implementing new business ideas.
- Worked with Page Layouts, Tabs, Custom fields, Custom objects, Validation Rules

Full Stack Developer Intern

1/2019-5/2019

SRL Group

- Created a fast and responsive mobile-friendly website using Angular/HTML5/CSS/Bootstrap
- Led software development projects using Agile/Scrum development process

EDUCATION

New Jersey Institute of Technology

9/2015-5/2019

Newark, NJ

- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, GPA 3.55/4.0
- Graduated Cum Laude